And the teacher had already instructed her to stay out of the boys' bathroom. And she had drank two glasses of that red juice at the Halloween party, and I mean, who can resist that red juice, right? It's so good. And she couldn't hold her pee any longer. Her and her classmates were four years old. They already felt empowered enough to police her use of the so-called public bathrooms. She was four years old. She had already been taught the brutal lesson that there was no bathroom door at preschool with a sign on it that welcomed people like her. She'd already learned that bathrooms were going to be a problem, and that problem started with her and was hers alone. So my friend asked me to talk to her little daughter, and I did. I wanted to tell her that me and her mom were going to march on down and talk to that school, and the problem was going to go away, but I knew that wasn't true. I wanted to tell her that it was all going to get better when she got older, but I couldn't. So I asked her to tell me the story of what had happened, asked her to tell me how it made her feel. "Mad and sad," she told me. So I told her that she wasn't alone
El profesor le advirtió que no fuese al baño de los chicos. Un día se bebió dos vasos de ese zumo de color rojo en la fiesta de Halloween. ¿Quién es capaz de resistirse? Ese zumo rojo es muy rico. No se podía aguantar el pipí mucho más. Ella y sus compañeros tenían cuatro años. Sus compañeros ya creían tener la potestad de controlar el uso que esta niña podría hacer de los denominados baños públicos. Era una niña de cuatro años. Ya le habían dado una lección brutal: no había ningún baño en su jardín de infancia que tuviese una señal que diese la bienvenida a personas como ella. Acababa de aprender que el cuarto de baño sería un problema. Un problema que sería de ella y solo para ella. Mi amiga me pidió que hablase con la niña y hablé con ella. Quería decirle que su madre y yo íbamos a hablar con su colegio para solucionar el problema. Pero yo sabía que no era verdad. Quería decirle que todo sería más fácil cuando creciese, pero tampoco podía. Le pedí que me contase lo que había ocurrido y le pedí que me contase cómo se sentía. "Enfadada y triste", me dijo. Y le dije que no estaba sola
and that it wasn't right what had happened to her, and then she asked me if I had ever peed in my pants before. I said yes, I had, but not for a really long time. (Laughter) Which of course was a lie, because you know how you hit, like, 42 or 43, and sometimes you just, I don't know, you pee a little bit when you cough or sneeze, when you're running upstairs, or you're stretching. Don't lie. It happens. Right? She doesn't need to know that, I figure. (Laughter) I told her, when you get older, your bladder is going to grow bigger, too. When you get old like me, you're going to be able to hold your pee for way longer, I promised her. "Until you can get home?" she asked me. I said, "Yes, until you can get home." She seemed to take some comfort in that. So let's just build some single stall, gender-neutral bathrooms with a little bench for getting changed into your gym clothes. We can't change the world overnight for our children, but we can give them a safe and private place to escape that world, if only for just a minute. This we can do. So let's just do it. And if you are one of those people who is sitting out there right now already coming up with a list of reasons in your head why this is not a priority, or it's too expensive, or telling yourself that giving a trans person a safe place to pee
y que lo que le había pasado no estaba bien. Me preguntó que si alguna vez me había hecho pipí encima. Le dije que sí, pero no por mucho tiempo. (Risas) También es mentira, porque ya saben que cuando se cumplen los 40, a veces se escapa el pipí al toser o al estornudar al subir las escaleras o al hacer estiramientos. No digan mentiras. Esto ocurre, ¿verdad? No creo que a esta niña le haga falta saber estas cosas. (Risas) Le dije que, cuando crecemos, la vejiga también crece. "Cuando crezcas como yo, podrás aguantarte el pipí más tiempo". Se lo prometí. "¿Hasta llegar a casa?", me preguntó. Le dije que sí. "Sí, hasta llegar a casa". Y, al parecer, eso la consoló en parte. ¿Por qué no instalamos baños unisex y unipersonales con un pequeño banco para cambiarse de ropa para educación física? No podemos cambiar el mundo de la noche a la mañana para nuestros hijos, pero podemos darles un lugar íntimo y seguro para refugiarse de ese mundo, aunque solo sea por unos minutos. Podemos hacerlo. Hagámoslo. Si alguno de Uds. ya está pensando en una lista de razones por las que este asunto no es prioritario o que es demasiado caro o que le niegue a una persona transexual un espacio seguro donde ir al baño
or get changed in supports a lifestyle choice that you feel offends your morality, or your masculinity, or your religious beliefs, then let me just appeal to the part of your heart that probably, hopefully,
o cambiarse de ropa, Uds. apoyan la elección de un estilo de vida que ofende sus valores o su masculinidad o sus creencias religiosas. Déjeme apelarles a esa parte de sus corazones que, probablemente, se preocupe
does care about the rest of the population. If you can't bring yourself to care enough about people like me, then what about women and girls with body image issues? What about anyone with body image stuff going on? What about that boy at school who is a foot shorter than his classmates,
por el resto de la población. ¿Si a Ud. no le importa el bienestar de gente como yo, qué me dice de esas mujeres y niñas con problemas de imagen? ¿Qué me dice de alguien que tenga problemas de percepción de su imagen? ¿Qué pasa con el chico que es el bajito de su clase
whose voice still hasn't dropped yet? Hey? Oh, grade eight, what a cruel master you can be. Right? What about people with anxiety issues? What about people with disabilities or who need assistance in there? What about folks with bodies who, for whatever reason, don't fit into the mainstream idea of what a body should look like? How many of us still feel shy or afraid to disrobe in front of our peers, and how many of us allow that fear to keep us from something as important as physical exercise? Would all those people not benefit from these single stall facilities? We can't change transphobic minds overnight, but we can give everybody a place to get changed in so that we can all get to work making the world safer for all of us. Thank you for listening. (Applause) Thank you.
y al que todavía no le ha cambiado la voz? Ay, la adolescencia en la escuela, qué cruel puede llegar a ser. ¿Verdad? ¿Qué me dicen de las personas con problemas de ansiedad, de las personas con discapacidades que necesitan atención en esos lugares? ¿Qué me dicen de la gente cuyo cuerpo, por algún motivo, no encaja con los cánones que dictan nuestra apariencia? ¿A cuántos nos avergüenza quitarnos la ropa delante de nuestros compañeros y cuántos vamos a permitir que ese temor nos prohíba disfrutar de algo tan importante como la actividad física? ¿No nos beneficiaríamos todos de estos baños unipersonales? No podemos cambiar de repente todas esas mentes transfóbicas, pero podemos darle a todo el mundo un espacio donde cambiarse para poder llegar al trabajo y hacer de este mundo un lugar más seguro para todos nosotros. Gracias por su atención. (Aplausos) Gracias.